Will Lotherington

■ will.lotherington@hey.com 🔻 wLotherington.com 🕠 wLotherington 🗣 Chicago, IL | San Francisco, CA

PROFILE

I'm a software engineer with multiple years of experience in both the JavaScript and Ruby ecosystems, and am comfortable with AWS and Docker. I am the co-creator of Ekko (ekko-realtime.com ☑), an open-source framework that provides realtime infrastructure and in-transit message processing for web applications.

EXPERIENCE

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, *Ekko (ekko-realtime.com)* \Box

2021 - present

- Created Ekko, an open-source framework for building real-time applications with in-transit message processing.
- Designed, prototyped, and built Ekko using Node.js and Amazon Web Services (ECS Fargate, ELB, IAM, Lambda, S3).
- Led Ekko client SDK development that enabled developers to easily interact with Ekko server (JavaScript).
- Developed scalable cloud infrastructure for tens of thousands of WebSockets connections and Lambda invocations.
- Containerized Ekko server code for deployment to AWS cloud infrastructure (Docker, ECR, ECS Fargate).
- Automated AWS infrastructure deployment and teardown (Cloud Development Kit, CloudFormation templates, SDK).
- Worked on CLI tool for Ekko setup, infrastructure deployment/teardown, and Lambda management (oclif, JavaScript).
- Load tested Ekko with artillery.io to simulate 50,000 connections and 1 million messages sent in 100 seconds.
- Produced all front-end assets and animations for Ekko demos, case study website, and presentation.
- Authored Ekko's technical case study: https://ekko-realtime.com/#case-study

Full Stack Developer, *Self Employed*

2018 - 2021

- RequestBin A database-backed application for receiving and debugging webhooks (Node.js, PostgreSQL, Socket.IO).
- Reaction Trello-like collaboration app (MongoDB, Node.js/Express, React/Redux).
- Ruby Reps Executable spaced repetition flashcards for Ruby (Ruby, JavaScript, jQuery, Sinatra, PostgreSQL).
- Postit Reddit-like social app (Bootstrap, Rails, PostgreSQL, Twilio).
- Dijkstra's Trip Airline routing application leveraging Dijkstra's algorithm to find the shortest path (Node.js, React).

Various Positions, Keyence Corporation of America

2014 - 2020

- Promoted quickly held 5 roles in 6 years each with increased technical responsibilities and business strategy influence.
- Developed process improvement tools used by thousands of employees across various departments and affiliates.

SKILLS

Languages (JavaScript, Node.js, Ruby, SQL, HTML, CSS, Go)

Frameworks (Express.js, Handlebars, React.js, Redux, Sinatra, Erb, Ruby on Rails, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap)

Cloud (Amazon Web Services (ALB, DynamoDB, EC2, ECR, ECS Fargate, IAM, Lambda, S3, SDK), Digital Ocean, Heroku)

Technologies (Git/GitHub, Docker, HTTP, JSON Web Token, PostgreSQL, Redis, REST APIs, WebSockets Linux)

EDUCATION